ILGWU. Leon Stein papers 5780/087
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Cahan Draft Volume 2, 1926 (Box 12, Folder 9)
- Cahan Draft Volume 3 (Box 12, Folder 10)
- Newspaper Photographs and Articles, 1939-1944 (Box 12, Folder 11)
- The Education of Abraham Cahan Draft Volume 1 (Box 12, Folder 12)
- Notes for Cahan Draft Volume 1 (Box 12, Folder 13)
- Cahan Draft Part 2 (Box 12, Folder 14)
- Cahan Draft Chapters 2-6 (Box 12, Folder 15)
- Cahan Draft Chapters 7-10 (Box 12, Folder 16)
- Cahan Draft Chapters 11-12 and Notes (Box 12, Folder 17)
- Collection of Newspaper Clippings on Labor Struggles in Michigan and Colorado, 1913-1914 (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Ledger Book (Box 13, Folder 2)
- History of Sewing Machines Pamphlets, 1867-1970 (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Notes on Ludlow Massacre (Box 13, Folder 4)
- "Three Feminist Bibles" Draft by Leon Stein (Box 13, Folder 5)
- Jewish Publication Society of America Documents, 1966-1970 (Box 13, Folder 6)
- American Historical Society Documents, 1974-1975 (Box 13, Folder 7)
- Arno Press Documents, 1975-1979 (Box 13, Folder 8)
- Out of the Sweatshop Documents, 1977-1978 (Box 13, Folder 9)
- Personal Letters, 1977-1978 (Box 13, Folder 10)
- Personal Correspondence, 1962-1968 (Box 13, Folder 11)
- Leaves From My Life Draft by Abraham Cahan, 1926 (Box 13, Folder 12)
- B.B.C. Documents, 1977-1978 (Box 13, Folder 13)
- "American Labor: From Conspiracy to Collective Bargaining" Pamphlet, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  By Leon Stein and Philip Taft
- Articles and Letters, 1963-1975 (Box 13, Folder 15)
- ILPA Ethics Report Draft, 1957 (Box 13, Folder 16)
- Letters, 1957-1979 (Box 13, Folder 17)
- "A Brief Statement of Programs and Activities" By The American Council on Education, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 18)
- "A Book That Helped Mold European Socialist Attitudes Toward American Labor" by Elly Borochowicz, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  December, 1970. In English, French, and German
- Cahan Documents, 1969-1970 (Box 13, Folder 20)
- Ludlow Documents, 1961-1972 (Box 13, Folder 21)
- Rejected Art for Cahan Book (Box 13, Folder 22)
- Notable American Women Documents, 1975-1977 (Box 13, Folder 23)
- Labor History Journal Documents, 1969-1977 (Box 13, Folder 24)
- Labor History Television Documents, 1975-1978 (Box 13, Folder 25)
- Rabbi Jacob Joseph Documents, 1919-1959 (Box 13, Folder 26)
- Justice Documents, 1962-1975 (Box 13, Folder 27)
- Women and Labor Articles, 1887-1907 (Box 13, Folder 28)
- Letters, 1966-1976 (Box 13, Folder 29)
- "The Sense of History and the Annals of Labor" by Maurice F. Newfeld, 1961 (Box 13, Folder 30)
- Humanities Documents, 1975-1977 (Box 13, Folder 31)
- ILGWU Documents, 1963-1977 (Box 13, Folder 32)
- Letters and Articles, 1975-1980 (Box 13, Folder 33)
- Photograph [folder removed to 5780/087 P] (Box 14, Folder 1)
- "U.S. Labor Editors Look at Israel", 1974 (Box 14, Folder 2)
- "Book-of-the-Month Club News", 1962 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  April
- Letters, 1976-1978 (Box 14, Folder 4)
- Pamphlets and Newspapers, 1967-1980 (Box 14, Folder 5)
- Pamphlets, 1890-1900 (Box 14, Folder 6)
- Letters and Articles, 1925-1975 (Box 14, Folder 7)
- Photographs [folder removed to 5780/087 P] (Box 14, Folder 8)
- Letters and Newspapers, 1962-1976 (Box 14, Folder 9)
- Poems by Leon Stein (Box 14, Folder 10)
- Articles by Leon Stein, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 11)
- New York City Bicentennial Documents, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 12)
- Brooklyn Museum Documents, 1975-1976 (Box 14, Folder 13)
- Cornell ILR Documents, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 14)
- Letters, 1967-1980 (Box 14, Folder 15)
- Odes to Stanley Grubman by Barbara Stein (Box 14, Folder 16)
- Justice Newspapers, 1956-1968 (Box 14, Folder 17)
- Letters, Notes, and Pamphlets, 1973-1980 (Box 14, Folder 18)
- New York Council for Humanities Documents, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 19)
- Letters and Articles, 1977-1980 (Box 14, Folder 20)
- Humanities Articles and Speeches by Leon Stein, 1979-1980 (Box 14, Folder 21)
- Letters, 1953-1968 (Box 14, Folder 22)
- "Section Work in the Women's Garment Industry" by Nathan Belfer, 1954 (Box 14, Folder 23)
- "Made in U.S.A. The Untold Story of Workers in America", 1979 (Box 14, Folder 24)
- Letters, 1962-1968 (Box 14, Folder 25)
- "The New Deal in the Dress Industry" by Dr. N.I. Stone, 1941 (Box 14, Folder 26)
- Drawing of the Cloakmaker's Strike in Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, 1890 (Box 14, Folder 27)
- Election Day 1944 Draft by Leon Stein (Box 14, Folder 28)
- Draft (Box 14, Folder 29)
- Letters and Contracts, 1960-1965 (Box 14, Folder 30)
- Letters, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 31)
- Statements and Newspapers, 1953-1982 (Box 14, Folder 32)
- "The Great Flanken War of 1902" by Leon Stein (Box 14, Folder 33)
- Edited Draft of The Triangle Fire by Leon Stein, 1961 (Box 14, Folder 34)
- Triangle Fire Notes (Box 14, Folder 35)
- Triangle Fire Notes (Box 14, Folder 36)
- Triangle Fire Notes (Box 14, Folder 37)
- Images and Photographs [folder removed to 5780/087 P] (Box 14, Folder 38)
- Draft (Box 14, Folder 39)
- International Fire Fighter Magazine, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 40)
  November
- Notes and Newspaper Clippings, 19111911 (Box 14, Folder 41)
- Draft (Box 14, Folder 42)
- Letters, 1958 (Box 14, Folder 43)
- Justice Newspaper, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 44)
  March
- Draft and Notes (Box 14, Folder 45)
- Triangle Fire Documents, 1913-1961 (Box 14, Folder 46)
- Triangle Fire Draft (Box 15, Folder 1)
- Drafts (Box 15, Folder 2)
- Notes and Drafts (Box 15, Folder 3)
- Articles (Box 15, Folder 4)
  In English and French
- Collection of Articles, 1858-1950 (Box 15, Folder 5)
- Drafts and Articles (Box 15, Folder 6)
- Letters and Contracts, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 7)
- "Socialism, Democracy and the Church" by Frederick Ryan, 1984 (Box 15, Folder 8)
- "Francis Sheehy-Skeffington - Democratic Socialist and Feminist" by Manus O'Riordan, 1985 (Box 15, Folder 9)
- "The Rise and Fall of Irish Anti-Semitism", 1984 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  The 1904 Campaign by Pat Feeley and The Sinn Fein Tradition by Manus O'Riordan
- "Sinn Fein and Reaction" by Frederick Ryan, 1984 (Box 15, Folder 11)
- Letters, Speeches, and Drafts, 1982-1983 (Box 15, Folder 12)
- Photographs and Negatives [folder removed to 5780/087 P] (Box 15, Folder 13)
- Letters, 1949-1964 (Box 15, Folder 14)
- Jacob Stein Documents, 1925-1976 (Box 15, Folder 15)
- Personal Documents, 1964-1980 (Box 15, Folder 16)
- Photographs [folder removed to 5780/087 P] (Box 15, Folder 17)
- Justice Trip to Israel Letters, 1971-1988 (Box 15, Folder 18)
- Grant Applications and Letters, 1979-1983 (Box 15, Folder 19)
- Street and Smith's New York Weekly, 1871 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  May 25
- Labor and the Humanities, 1981 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  March and August
- The Milwaukee Journal, 1911 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  March 27
- Harper's Bazaar, 1896 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  June 6
- The American Labor Museum Letter and Pamphlet, 1985 (Box 15, Folder 24)
- Letters, 1963-1984 (Box 15, Folder 25)
- "Thomas Jefferson - Gerontologist" by Leon Stein, 1981 (Box 15, Folder 26)
- Jewish Life, 1954 (Box 15, Folder 27)
- Letters, 1982-1985 (Box 15, Folder 28)
- "The Cloakmakers' Strike" Draft by Leon Stein (Box 15, Folder 29)
- Introduction by Leon Stein, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 30)
  Ninth Jefferson Lecture, April 24
- Some Problems in the 'Humanization of Work' Draft by Koji Okubayashi (Box 15, Folder 31)
- Letters, 1972-1978 (Box 15, Folder 32)
- A Book of Ayres by John Bartlett, 1606 (Box 15, Folder 33)
  Transcribed, Scored, and Edited by Edmund Horace Fellowes
- Second Book of Ayres by William Corkine, 1612 (Box 15, Folder 34)
- Fifty Songs Selected From the Works of John Dowland (Box 15, Folder 35)
- First Book Of Airs by Thomas Morley, 1600 (Box 15, Folder 36)
- Photographs [folder removed to 5780/087 P] (Box 15, Folder 37)
- Letters, 1979-1983 (Box 16, Folder 1)
- Triangle Fire Articles, 1983 (Box 16, Folder 2)
- Articles by Leon Stein (Box 16, Folder 3)
- "A Mensch is Born" by Harlan Jacobson, 1984 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  In Voice July 3
- New York Council for the Humanities Annual Report, 1977-1978 (Box 16, Folder 5)
- Photographs [folder removed to 5780/087 P] (Box 16, Folder 6)
- Report of the Joint Relief Committee on the Triangle Fire Disaster, 1913 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  January 15
- Election Day 1944 Draft by Leon Stein (Box 16, Folder 8)
- 'What the Union Means to Me" by Miriam Spicehandler (Box 16, Folder 9)
- Poems by Walter Alan Stein (Box 16, Folder 10)
- Convention Reports of the ILGWU, 1916-1924 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  Thirteenth through Seventeenth
- "The Role of Women in American History" (Box 16, Folder 12)
- Llewellyn Book Documents, 1986-1987 (Box 16, Folder 13)
- "The Great Flanken War of 1902" Draft by Leon Stein (Box 16, Folder 14)
- Notes (Box 16, Folder 15)
- "Gompers-Hillquit Debate" Justice Labor Day Feature, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  September 1
- Receipts and Letters, 1938-1962 (Box 16, Folder 17)
- Reading with a Purpose Pamphlets, 1925-1927 (Box 16, Folder 18)
- Photographs [folder removed to 5780/087 P] (Box 16, Folder 19)
- Pamphlets (Box 16, Folder 20)
- Letters, 1943-1988 (Box 16, Folder 21)
- Articles and Newspapers, 1951-1997 (Box 16, Folder 22)
- Thirty-two Picture Postcards of Old New York Selected by Hayward Cirker, 1976 (Box 16, Folder 23)
- Photographs and Images [folder removed to 5780/087 P] (Box 16, Folder 24)
- "Care of the Back", 1953 (Box 16, Folder 25)
  By William K. Ishmael and Howard B. Shorbe
- "Portal to America: The Lower East Side" by Allon Schoener, 1967 (Box 16, Folder 26)
- "American Labor: From Conspiracy to Collective Bargaining" Created by Leon Stein and Philip Taft, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 27)
- School Papers and Insurance Policies, 1954-1957 (Box 16, Folder 28)
- Letters, 1939-1985 (Box 16, Folder 29)
- Miscellaneous Personal Documents, 1973-1979 (Box 16, Folder 30)
- Articles and Pamphlets, 1952-1977 (Box 16, Folder 31)
- Pamphlets, 1945-1982 (Box 16, Folder 32)
- "Cartoons from the 1950s in the ILGWU Justice" by Bernard Seaman, 1959 (Box 16, Folder 33)
- Letters, 1995-1996 (Box 16, Folder 34)
- Letters and Mail, 1990-1995 (Box 16, Folder 35)
- Photographs and Images [folder removed to 5780/087 P] (Box 16, Folder 36)
- Pamphlets, 1981-1988 (Box 16, Folder 37)
- "The Forum" by the Forum Publishing Company, 1890 (Box 16, Folder 38)
- Sheet Music (Box 16, Folder 39)
  In Dutch
- Pamphlets, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 40)
- Index Cards (Box 17)
  Three index card file boxes.
- Marble paperweight. "International Labor Press Association. AFL-CIO/CLC" (Box 17)
- Bronze medal. "First Union Health Center Fiftieth Anniversary, 1914-1964" (Box 17)
  2000 of these were struck by the US Mint. Act of Congress authorizing the medals was the last bill signed by President John F. Kennedy.
- Nancy Bogan Interview with Mrs. Sophie Shulman, 1987 (Box 17)
  11Nov87. Audio cassette tape.
- News Stories. Ludlow (Box 17)
  3.25 inch open-reel audio tape
- [No title] (Box 18, Folder 1)
  Includes 3 oversize images. Two appear to be newspaper reproductions; one drawing